Contact

ebhagens@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/emily-hagens-43711413 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Interpersonal Communication Abilities

Organization & prioritization skills
Team Leadership

Certifications

Registered Nurse Registered Nurse

Oncology Certified Nurse

Emily Hagens

Nurse Director at Brigham and Women's Hospital Chicago, Illinois

Summary

Experienced Registered Nurse with a history of working in the hospital & health care industry interested in health care leadership and operations. Completed master's for Adult Clinical Nurse Specialist / Health Systems Management MSN from Johns Hopkins University in 2018.

Experience

Brigham and Women's Hospital Nurse Director, Oncology October 2019 - Present (10 months) Boston, MA, United States

UChicago Medicine

6 years 1 month

Patient Care Manager, Hospitalist Medicine / Oncology November 2018 - October 2019 (1 year)

Chicago, Illinois

Assistant Patient Care Manager, Oncology December 2015 - November 2018 (3 years) Chicago, II

Staff Nurse, Oncology October 2013 - December 2015 (2 years 3 months)

Chicago, II

- -Served as Quality Chair on unit based council (UBC), active UBC member.
- -Served on organization-wide C. diff reduction work group.
- -Super user for Bar Code Medication Administration conversion.
- -Charge nurse.
- -Primary preceptor for 3 new graduate nurses.

Day-to-day job functions included: Providing patient-centered care to patients with complex Oncology and Hematology diagnoses in a 36-bed inpatient unit

Functioning regularly in the role of charge nurse on the unit, collaborating with peers to address and manage needs for each shift Assisting in the orientation of new staff members. Actively participating in quality initiatives at both the system and unit-specific levels.

Loyola Medicine

3 years

Staff Nurse, per diem

October 2013 - December 2015 (2 years 3 months)

Maywood, IL

- -Provided care for patients with a variety of Medical Oncology diagnoses on a 32-bed inpatient unit
- -Facilitated communication between all members of the interdisciplinary care team
- -Promoted providing optimal care of patients during inpatient stays by participating in quality data collection and audits

Staff Nurse, Oncology January 2013 - October 2013 (10 months) Maywood, Illinois

- -Provided care for patients with a variety of Medical Oncology diagnoses on a 32-bed inpatient unit
- -Facilitated communication between all members of the interdisciplinary care team
- -Promoted providing optimal care of patients during inpatient stays by participating in quality data collection and audits

Brigham and Women's Faulkner Hospital
Department of Professional Practice and Development Intern
June 2011 - October 2012 (1 year 5 months)

Greater Boston Area

- -Supported Department of Professional Practice and Development in the planning and implementation of hospital-wide initiatives.
- -Created customized SharePoint sites for hospital committees and provided education and technical support
- -Assisted in synthesizing and presenting data collection findings to Nursing Executive Board from various project roll-outs

Education

The Johns Hopkins University

Master's Degree, Clinical Nurse Specialist / Health Systems Management $MSN \cdot (2015 - 2018)$

Simmons College

Bachelor of Science (B.S.), Nursing - Business Management Dual major, Biology minor \cdot (2008 - 2012)

Boston University

· (2007 - 2008)